#### Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/philipp-blankenagel (LinkedIn)

## Top-Kenntnisse

Social Media
Public Relations
Marketing

# Languages

Deutsch (Native or Bilingual) Englisch (Full Professional) Spanisch (Elementary)

### Honors-Awards

#30u30

PR Report Award 2016 in Business-to-Business

#### **Publications**

"Das Klima wird rauer": Wie sechs Experten die Perspektiven der Fintech-Branche für das Jahr 2019 sehen

Worauf Startups bei der Konferenz-Teilnahme achten sollten

# Philipp Blankenagel

VP Marketing & Communications at re:cap Köln

# Zusammenfassung

Executive communicator and B2B Marketeer with startup, venture capital and corporate experience. Love to build brands, tell stories and steer companies through challenging situations by building and maintaining trust with relevant stakeholders. Corporate spokesperson and consultant to the senior management with several years of experience. I help companies to build their brand awareness by creating, executing and evaluating Communications and Marketing strategies around Digital, PR, Content, Social Media, Events and Brand.

# Berufserfahrung

re:cap
VP Marketing & Communications

Januar 2022 - Present (4 Monate)

# &Blankenagel

Communications & Strategy Consultant April 2020 - Present (2 Jahre 1 Monat)

Köln, Nordrhein-Westfalen

Strategy, Communications and PR support for digital companies in fast-paced growth environments

Capnamic Ventures
Head of Marketing & Communications
August 2020 - März 2022 (1 Jahr 8 Monate)

Köln, Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland

Leading all marketing and communications efforts for the Cologne / Berlin / Munich based early-stage VC Capnamic Ventures. Conducted an extensive rebranding. Communicated a 200m USD fund. Support and sparring for portfolio companies in regards to branding, positioning and communications. Funding round communication.

#### Solarisbank AG

4 Jahre 1 Monat

Vice President Communications & Marketing September 2018 - März 2020 (1 Jahr 7 Monate) Berlin

- Leading the integrated Corporate Communications & Marketing team, which is responsible for all earned, paid and owned media
- Main responsibilities include global key messaging, press relations, content strategy, positioning of senior management, social media, event strategy, amongst others

# Head of Communications Januar 2017 - September 2018 (1 Jahr 9 Monate) Berlin

- In charge of external as well as internal communications at solarisBank AG, the first fully licensed banking platform
- Responsible for international PR, communications, social media and event speaking at solarisBank
- Building up and leading the communications team
- Spokesperson
- Responsible for positioning of executive board members

# Communications Manager

März 2016 - Januar 2017 (11 Monate)

Berlin und Umgebung, Deutschland

- Built up communications and brand positioning prior to the launch of solarisBank
- Responsible for communications and PR as well as social media and events after the launch
- Spokesperson

#### FinLeap

Communications & Marketing September 2015 - Februar 2016 (6 Monate)

Berlin und Umgebung, Deutschland

finleap, the leading European fintech company builder, was founded by Hitfox Group (now IONIQ Group) in 2014 and hence in the beginning Hitfox and finleap shared a joint Marketing & Communications team. For Hitfox and finleap I was working on:

- Press relations for various startups (in the fields of fintech and big data)
- Brand building and positioning

- Online Marketing
- Reputation Management
- Social Media

#### Bosch

Working student: Internal Communications & Brand Marketing Januar 2013 - Juni 2015 (2 Jahre 6 Monate)

- Internal communications, process improvement, Enterprise 2.0, Brand Marketing

#### Deutsche Bank

Various internships in PR, Social Media and journalism 2011 - 2012 (1 Jahr)

Internships at:

Deutsche Bank (2012) - as part of the Corporate Comms team, focus on Social Media

ZDF (2011-12) - as part of the Social Media team of heute.de Scholz & Friends (2011) - intern for PR & Public Affairs SWR (2011) - online journalism internship

# Ausbildung

Universität Hohenheim

Master of Science (M.Sc.), Kommunikationsmanagement · (2012 - 2015)

Stellenbosch University/Universiteit Stellenbosch Marketing/Marketing-Management, allgemein · (2014 - 2014)

Johannes Gutenberg-Universität Mainz

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Publizistik & Politikwissenschaft · (2008 - 2012)

Universitetet i Agder (UiA)

The European Union and Domestic Public Administration · (2010 - 2010)